

✓ lovelliariesti@yahoo.co.id✓ +62811✓ Jakarta, Indonesia

f lovelli.fuad

v lovellifuad

in ariesti

ariesti

EDUCATION

University of Indonesia

Bachelor's Degree, Faculty of Humanities, 2002

Coursera

Data Scientist, Data Science, 2014 Web Design, Responsive Web Design, 2017

Google Analytics Academy

Data Scientist, Google Analytics, 2016

Hubspot Academy

Inbound Marketing Certified, Digital Marketing, 2017

Google News Lab

Training, Data Journalism, 2017

SUMMARY

I am passionate about helping businesses take off and making sure businesses and workforces get healthier and more productive. I create content that provides insight on my area of consultancy, as well as valuables out of my hobbies and weekend projects, where I test websites, apps, digital products, tech gadget to provide feedback. I review products that are not books, too, but I'm keeping it to just fashion and food at the moment.

I am dedicated to partnering with innovators to discover if and how we can provide a better user experience for our products and services. I once completed a data science specialization course and currently I am taking classes on data visualization and data journalism. My qualifications include certifications on data science, responsive web design, digital marketing, arts and culture.

To sum up, I am a writer, editor, and enlightened illustrator who is now starting my own art practice under The Minimal Web.

SKILLS

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE: Adobe Illustrator CC, Adobe Photoshop CC, Adobe Dreamweaver CC, Adobe InDesign CC

DIGITAL ARTS: Processing, ArtRage, Digital Photography

WRITING & CONTENT: Feature Writing, Content Writing, Copywriting, Editing, Creative Writing, Blogging, Articles, Essay Writing

DIGITAL MARKETING: Blogging, Inbound, Content Marketing

EMPLOYMENT

ARIESTI

Freelance writer and illustrator

As a freelancer I take up projects in the areas of copywriting, creative writing, translation and interpretation, and tutoring.

VERBALIZEIT

Translator/Interpreter

VerbalizeIt has recently been acquired by another startup. It is now called Smartling.

REV TRANSCRIPTION

Transcriptionist/Captioner

Jakarta, Indonesia Nov 2002 to Current

New York, NY Mar 2013 to Feb 2016

San Francisco, CA Nov 2015 to Mar 2016

PROJECTS

THE MINIMAL WEB Jan 2017 to Jan 2018

The Minimal Web is my take on starting an art practice. The idea was conceived after taking a few courses on Skillshare, and as a final or mid-term project I began compiling materials in-between my hours for the website. It is a work in progress that is planned to start taking off mid-2017.

THE FREELANCE SPIRIT Feb 2017 to Current

Exploring freelance work in Asia and the World, I have created and compiled materials to educate myself and others who would probably benefit from the knowledge. For example: the difference between "working from home" and "remote work", types of businesses for a beginning freelancer, etc.

AWARDS

University of Indonesia · PARTICIPANT IN RESEARCH PROPOSAL DESIGN TRAINING

Mar 2005

A group of selected lecturers were provided a chance to take part in this internal training and successful candidates were handed out certificates.

The Jakarta Fashion & Food Festival \cdot GADING NEWS AWARD 2ND PLACE: NEWS CATEGORY

May 2008

 $The \textit{Jakarta Fashion \& Food Festival is an annual event held every \textit{May since 2006.} I took \textit{part in 2008 as I was taking up a one-year journalism training with the \textit{Jakarta Post Training Department.} \\$

ACTIVITIES

THE FREELANCE SPIRIT · Founder

THE MINIMAL WEB · Founder/Illustrator

Feb 2017 to Current

Jan 2017 to Current

My first project is to create an author website for myself. Currently this is the design and planning phase, with the soft launch date planned to be somewhere in March, 2017.

VOLUNTEERING

TRANSLATORS WITHOUT BORDERS · Translator Jakarta. Indonesia

Jul 2014 to Current